ARIFUR RAHMAN

Address: Ho# B/19, Al-Kamal Housing, Zoo Road, Mirpur-2,, Shah Ali, Dhaka

Primary Mobile No: 01841246103 Secondary Mobile No: 01590037177 Emergency Contact No: 01818813814

Primary Email : arifur.rahman.attire@gmail.com Alternate Email : mqrahman@yahoo.com



Career Objective:

To serve myself as an efficient & positive employee for the field of HR, Administration and Compliance. I want to prove that- positive attitude, hard labour & honesty effort makes someone successful in the field of job or even in business arena.

Career Summary:

I am a professional person in the field of Admin, HR and Compliance where I can contribute effectively for my company. I also want to utilize my learning of my one & half decades field work experience. Over the years of my professional career, my leadership, team work, hard labour, decision making ability makes me perfect contributor. My education, working experience in long year and different training makes me a viable candidate for the field of human resource, admin and compliance.

Special Qualification:

Having long years experience to handle below: *Buyer-H&M, Wal mart, M&S, Kapphal, Best Seller, Decathlon, Tesco *Achieving certificate-WRAP, ISO9001,C-TPAT, BSCI, SEDEX* Facing audit-Accord, Alliance, BSCI, WRAP, SEDEX, ISO 9001: 2015

Employment History:

Total Year of Experience: 20.8 yrs

1. General Manager (HR, Admin & Compliance) (0 yr)

(November, 2022 - Continuing)

Chaity Composite Ltd. (Chaity Group)

Cotto Shilmondi, Tripordi, Sonargaon, Narayangonj

Area of Expertise

Admin and Protocol (0 yr), Compliance Management (0 yr), HR & Training (0 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities

* Responsible for all HR, Admin & Compliance related issues of Chaity Industrial Park.* Look after the housekeeping, transport, fire safety, security management.* Ensure strategic policy & procedures in aspect of Admin, HR & Compliance issues of CCL.* Ensure required compliance in the factory premises implemented as per buyer code of conduct.* Resolve employees grievance, stress in a proactive manner.BR* Responsible to handle recruitment, Orientation/Induction program, exit interview and final settlement etc.* Follow-up Attendance, Salary Admin, Leave Management, Compensation Benefit & incentive schemes.* Follow-up a sound Performance Mgt System of staffs & management personnel in the factory.* Ensuring factories prepared for audits like, Social compliance, technical & Security System Audit (CTPAT)* Maintain transport Management, Executive Food Management, waste Management.* Maintain Medical Centre, and Child Care * Handling Grievance Management & Disciplinary Issues of Factory. * Liaison with merchandising, Production and QA Department to coordinate with Buyers visits and take all necessary steps for facing the buyers/ Govt. and compliance visit and audit. * Ensure security of plant, properties, premises & personnel.. * Follow up expenditures like staff & workers salary & wages, overtime & night allowance, incentives, education allowance, Tiffin bill, Final settlement bill etc. * Responsible for Keep liaison with local government bodies like police, Gas office, Electricity Office etc.

2. Deputy General Manager (Administration) (1 yr)

(October, 2021 - October, 2022)

Fakir Fashion Limited

Dohargaon, Baliapara, Rupganj, Narayangonj

Area of Expertise

Administative (1 vr)

Duties/Responsibilities

* Responsible for develop, integrate and lead day-to-day key administrative functions of company.* Plan, control and supervise the functional efforts across the company, including canteen management, transportation, legal, facilities and equipment as well as safeguarding of intellectual property* Responsible of orientation and training of newly recruited administrative workers and staff* Face internal and external audit to find loopholes and execute corrective action plan to minimize the audit findings* Check and maintain the safety and security of factory owned outside property * Take measures and protection of the employees to eliminate hazards created by gravity, motion, mechanical, electrical, temperature, pressure, chemical, biological, radiation and lastly sound* Investigate to identify causes or to determine how incidents might be prevented for future in the factory compound.* Inspect or evaluate workplace environment and practices to ensure compliance with safety standards as per set regulations* Analyze need, develop and execute the support systems like housekeeping, preventive maintenance, office stationery, utilities, rent and parking management* Follow up shipments and logistics support services and shipment schedule for goods transport to port and other destinations* Effective liaison with local Govt. Authority, Law and order enforcing agencies as and when required* Expose to access control & time attendance system, firefighting system, evacuation procedure & emergency contact* Ensure efficient office management and logistic support for every department* Check and ensure the factories are prepared for buyers or third parties visit* Monitor and control proper disposal of wastage and effective waste management systems* Control and effective utilization of factory owned vehicles operation * Responsible for vehicle tracking system, servicing scheduling and route plan with supplier follow up. * Close follow up with medical center, & day care. * Maintain fare price shop, kitchen of staff, executives and buyers. * Over all responsible for maintain factory health & safety standard, working as the top of House-keeping team * Ensure safety & security of factory premises. Lead the security section of plant * Lead the fire safety team to keep the plant safe from fire incident.

3. DGM (HR, Admin & Compliance) (4.2 yrs)

(July, 2017 - October, 2021)

Attire Garden Limited (Sweater Manufacturer & Exporter))

Chaidana, Board Bazar, Gazipur

Area of Expertise

Factory HR Administration (1.5 yrs), General HR (1.5 yrs), Social Compliance and Sustainability. (1.2 yrs)

Duties/Responsibilities

* Lead HR, Admin and Compliance team for smooth operation of Sweater factory. * Providing support to implement HR and Administrative policies throughout the organization. * Work on administrative issues of plant like transport, housekeeping, canteen and dining facilities, food supply. * Excellent communication, decision making skills with positive approach to problem solving within all department * Industrial relations, safety and security of man and materials and welfare activities* Evaluate the progress of project* Ensuring TNA (Training Need Assessment) of employee, provide training and evaluate effectiveness of training. * Implement Quality Management System throughout the organization. * Lead the child care, medical center for smooth operation.

4. DGM (HR, Admin & Compliance) (3.4 yrs)

(January, 2014 - June, 2017)

Graphics Textiles Limited (A large knit composite factory)

Sreerampur, Sutipara, Kalampur, Dhamrai, Dhaka

Area of Expertise

Administrative (1.1 yrs), HRD (1.1 yrs), Social Compliance (1.1 yrs)

Duties/Responsibilities

* Concentrate on administrative issues like transport, house keeping, canteen and dining facilities, fresh water supply.* Excellent communication, decision making skills, positive approach to problem solving among all department.* Industrial relations, safety and security of man and materials and welfare activities* Evaluate the progress of project* Maintain compliance standard from view of social, quality and security compliance. * Necessary steps taken to control wastage and use maximum resources. * Handling healthy labour practice as for reward and punishment required. * Maintain report and record as required for smooth plant operation.

5. Sr. AGM (HR, Admin & Compliance) (0.9 yr)

(January, 2013 - December, 2013)

Graphics Textiles Limited

Sreerampur, Sutipara, Kalampur, Dhamrai, Dhaka

Area of Expertise

Administration (0.2 yr), Compliance Management (0.2 yr), Human Resources & Development (0.2 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities

Head of HR, Admin & Compliance team of the plant

6. AGM (HR, Admin & Compliance) (1.5 yrs)

(June, 2011 - December, 2012)

Graphics Textiles Limited

Sreerampur, Sutipara, Kalampur, Dhamrai, Dhaka

Area of Expertise

Administration (0.5 yr), HRD (0.5 yr), Social Compliance (0.5 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities

Head of HR, Admin & Compliance team of the plant

7. Manager - Admin, HR & Compliance (1.4 yrs)

(January, 2010 - June, 2011)

Apex Textile Printing Mills Ltd

Chandora, Kaliakoir, Gazipur.

Area of Expertise

Compliance (0.4 yr), Human Resources & Development (0.4 yr), Office Management (0.4 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities

- * Contribute to set a good HR, Admin and compliance standard within organization.
- * Orientation and training of new employee.
- * Arrange electrical safety, WPC meeting.
- * Prepare and establish company SOP and policy.
- * Maintain appraisal system to evaluate individual
- * Maintain payroll system of the company.
- * Arrange training on personal awareness, fire fighting, first aid and other compliance issues
- * Attending health and safety meeting, co-ordinate with safety members.

8. Asst. Manager (Admin & Compliance) (2 yrs)

(December, 2007 - December, 2009)

Apex Textile Printing Mills Limited

Chandora, Kaliakoir, Gazipur

Area of Expertise

Administration (0.7 yr), Compliance (0.7 yr), HR & Training (0.7 yr)

Duties/Responsibilities

Head of HR, Admin & Compliance team of the plant

9. Sr. Executive - (Admin Assistant to Sr. Executive) (5.6 yrs)

(May, 2002 - December, 2007)

SQ Sweaters Ltd. (SQ Group)

Concord IK Tower, Level 4, North Avenue, Gulshan-2, Dhaka-1212

Area of Expertise

Compensation & Benefits (1.8 yrs), Compliance (1.8 yrs), HR & Training (1.8 yrs)

Duties/Responsibilities

- * My contribution goes to implement activities as stipulated compliance & suppliers Code of Conduct of Company.
- * Closely monitor and coordinate with production dept for Admin & Compliance issues.
- * Ensure maternity benefit of all female workers.
- * Collect the grievance issues through all workers and any other means and take appropriate action.
- * Closely monitoring factory cleanliness.
- * Arrange monthly fire drill and to supervise all worker during fire drill.
- * Closely monitoring child day care center of the factory.
- * Prepare and submit reports as desired by the management.

Academic Qualification:

| Exam Title | Concentration/Major | Institute | Result | Pas.Year | Duration |
|--------------------------------|---------------------|-------------------------------------|--------------------------------|----------|----------|
| Master of Commerce (MCom) | Management | Jagannath University, Dhaka | Second Class, Marks :47% | 1999 | 2 Years |
| Bachelor of Commerce (BCom) | Commerce | Government Bangla College, Dhaka | Second Class, Marks :48% | 1997 | 2 Years |
| HSC | Science | Tejgaon College, Dhaka | Second Division, Marks :51% | 1995 | 2 Years |
| SSC | Science | BCIC College, Dhaka | First Division, Marks :79% | 1993 | 10 Years |

Training Summary:

| Training Title | Topic | Institute | Country | Location | Year | Duration |
|--|--|--|------------|--|------|----------|
| Training on Leadership | Leadership, Managerial Skills and Communication for seniors or team leaders. | Sapien Strategy Consulting & Research Ltd. | Bangladesh | FFL premise (HR Training Center). | 2022 | 2 days |
| Social Compliance Changes | Environmental & Safety Issues | SGS Bangladesh Limited | Bangladesh | Noor Tower, 110 Bir Uttam C R Datta Road, Dhaka | 2019 | 2 days |
| Bangladesh Labour Law & Labour Rules | Bangladesh Labour Law 2006 and Bangladesh Labour Rules 2015 | Graphics Textiles Limited | Bangladesh | GTL, Dhamrai, Dhaka | 2017 | 3 day |
| Domestic Inquiry | Necessaty & Practice of Domestic Inquiry in Garment Industry of Bangladesh | Institute of Personnel Management | Bangladesh | IPM, Farmgate, Dhaka | 2010 | 2 Days |
| Quality Management System Development | Quality Management System Development | SLTS | Bangladesh | Brac Centre, Mohakhali | 2010 | 2 Days |
| Training on WRAP & BSCI | 12 Principles of WRAP & Principles of BSCI | gtz & BGMEA | Bangladesh | Platinum Suites, H # 58, R # 11, Banani, Dhaka | 2010 | 2 Days |
| Social Compliance & SA 8000 | Social Compliance & SA 8000 | BRIDDHI | Bangladesh | Dhanmondi, Dhaka | 2006 | 4 Days |
| Internal Audit Technique | ISO 9001:2000 | Management Solution Inc. | Bangladesh | SQ Head Office | 2005 | 2 Day |
| Training on Social Compliance | Social Compliance | SQ GROUP | Bangladesh | Rangs Bhaban | 2004 | 5 Days |

Professional Qualification:

| Certification | Institute | Location | From | To |
|-----------------------|--------------------------------|------------|---------------|--------------|
| Computer Basic Course | Anand Computer Training Centre | Mirpur - 1 | March 3, 1999 | June 6, 1999 |

Career and Application Information:

Looking For : Top Level Job Available For : Full Time Present Salary : Tk. 250000 Expected Salary : Tk. 320000

Preferred Job Category : Garments/ Textile, General Management/Admin, HR/Org. Development

Preferred District : Dhaka, Gazipur, Habiganj

Preferred Country : Australia, Canada, Denmark, France, Germany, Italy, Japan, New Zealand

Preferred Organization Types : Manufacturing (FMCG), Multinational Companies, Garments, Textile, Buying House,

Group of Companies, Dyeing Factory

Specialization:

| Fields of Specialization | Description |
|--|---|
| Compensation & Benefits Compliance ISO 9001:2000 Job Analysis & Manpower Planning Labor Issues Labor Law Labor Management Performance appraisal Recruitment Training | * Handling Buyer - M&S, H&M, Otto, Tesco, Kapphal, Decathlan, Fruit of the loom, Best Seller. * Achieving certificate- WRAP, ISO9001,C-TPAT, Fair Trade, GOTS etc * Facing audit- BV,ITS,SGS,ALGI, UL etc & training on Internal Audit for ISO 9001:2004 & other version. |

Extra Curricular Activities:

I have few exercise of writing poem, noble. I am a good player of Football & Cricket.

Language Proficiency:

| Language | Reading | Writing | Speaking | |
|----------|---------|---------|----------|--|
| English | High | High | Medium | |
| Hindi | Low | Low | Medium | |
| Bangla | High | High | High | |

Personal Details:

Father's Name : Md. Anowar Hossain Mother's Name : Mrs. Amena Begum Date of Birth : November 10, 1977

: Male Gender Height (Meter) Weight (Kg) : 80 Marital Status : Married : Bangladeshi : 4156299051 Nationality National Id No. Religion : Islam Passport No : BN0242061 Passport Issue Date : 1/30/2017

Permanent Address : Ho# B/19, Al-Kamal Housing, Zoo Road, Mirpur-2,, Shah Ali, Dhaka

Current Location : Dhaka Blood Group : B+

Reference (s):

Reference: 01Reference: 02Name: Abu Nosor Md. ZahidA N M Salauddin RiponOrganization: PDS Multination GroupUniversity of DhakaDesignation: Country Manager (Compliance)Associate Professor, IER

PDS Multinational Group, Ho# 517/2, Road #

Address : 10, Baridhara DOHS, Dhaka

Phone (Off.) : Phone (Res.) :

Mobile : +8801755640312 E-Mail : abu.zahid@osgbd.com

Relation : Professional

+8801914959898 abu.salauddin@du.ac.bd

IER Department, Dhaka University, Dhaka

Relative